# DARIAN YANE

#### **PROFILE**

## Data Analyst, Python Developer, MBA and Bachelor's Degree in Economics

Functional and business analyst with more than 20 years of experience in banking, pharmaceutical, power generation and investment industries.

Analytical, organized, and highly resolutive profile.

The training and experience in various areas and industries, allows me to have a deep analysis of business needs, providing added value beyond data analysis.

#### **SKILLS**

Economics Finance
Investments Statistics

Mathematics Logic

Administration Business

Tableau Power BI

Excel (with Macros) Power Query

SQL Python

Django GIT

Pandas Numpy

Matplotlib CSS

HTML

## **CONTACT**

Mar del Plata, Argentina

(+54) 11-5311-7020

yanedarian.dev@gmail.com

darianyane.com

github.com/DarianYane

linkedin.com/in/darian-yane/

## **EDUCATION**

## GOOGLE DATA ANALYTICS PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE,

COURSERA, 2023

PYTHON, CODERHOUSE, 2022

### MASTER'S DEGREE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (MBA), UADE, 2020

Distinction: MAGNA CUM LAUDE

Average: 8,68 (2nd best course average)

#### BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN ECONOMICS, UBA, 2011

**ECONOMIC ACTUARY**, (abandoned, 27 subjects passed)

## WORK EXPERIENCE



12/2022 - currently

## INVESTMENT ANALYST/EDITOR, INVERSOR GLOBAL

09/2021 - 01/2023

• Referent of cryptocurrencies in the company. Wrote reports, starred in webinars, and was speaker on Youtube..

#### PROFESSOR "CRYPTOCURRENCIES AND FINTECH", CODERHOUSE

08/2022 - 10/2022

## FREELANCER (EXCEL), FIVERR

01-2021 - 09/2021

• Made all kinds of Excels on request, which included pivot tables, macros, filters, dynamic dropdowns, etc.

## DATA ANALYST, AES SERVICIOS AMÉRICA

08/2019 - 08/2020

- Collect, clean, analyze, reconcile and visualize data from different internal and external sources.
- Assist the business with problems that require data-driven solutions.
- Generate of reports on a monthly basis.
- KPI follow-up.
- Projections of the different variables of the sector.

## **Achievements**

- Created KPI reports using SAP, Excel, Power Query and Power BI.
- Automated tax payment processes using macros in Excel. Reduced the probability of erroneous payments to 0% and standardized the processing time, achieving a 70% reduction.
- Established Dashboards for each of the Accounts Payable countries.

You can see the rest of my professional experience at <a href="linkedin.com/in/darian-yane/">linkedin.com/in/darian-yane/</a>

# 

- <u>1st Place Tournament "ACBSP Company Game"</u>, Company Game, 2019
- Member of the <u>Argentine Team that participated in the 9th</u>
   <u>Southern Cone Olympiad</u>
   , Argentine Mathematical Olympiad
   (OMA), 1998
- <u>National Mention in the 13th Argentine Mathematical</u>
   <u>Olympiad</u>, Argentine Mathematical Olympiad (OMA), 1996

# **LANGUAGES**

**ENGLISH**, Advanced

PORTUGUESE, Advanced

**SPANISH**, Native